Today we will learn how to make a belt skirt for the girl on the screen.
You can find the basic belt skirt file download link in the top comment.
In this video, we will focus on how to make a belt skirt for the girl on the screen.
First, open the basic belt skirt file you downloaded.
Select the adjustment sheet tool, click and drag the mouse to select all 2D sheets.
After selecting, click the mouse right button and select hardening in the pop-up menu, then activate simulation.
After starting the simulation, check the overall wearing effect.
Freeze all the sheets except the front sheet of the belt skirt.
Freeze the unmodified sheets, which will help the production of the following costumes.
Next, let's take a look at the costume effect we are going to make today.
Since we only have the belt skirt on the outer layer, we need to remove the current balance of the sheets.
Use the adjustment sheet tool to select the front sheet of the belt skirt.
In the menu on the right-hand side, click to remove the unmodified sheets.
Then you will see the blue border around the front sheet of the belt skirt will disappear.
This means that the unmodified sheets have been removed.
Now let's create the paper effect on the front sheet of the belt skirt.
First, select the multi-sided line tool in the 2D window tool bar.
What we are going to do now is to draw some fold-over inner lines according to the fold effect in the reference picture.
However, even though the fold looks like it starts from the middle of the costume, we cannot start drawing the fold-over inner line from the middle of the sheet.
We need to draw a line that connects both ends to the outer line of the sheet so that the sheet is opened later.
If you have drawn the inner line in the 2D window,
the inner line in the 3D window will also appear in the same position.
When you have completed the inner line, refer to the 3D window effect and use the edit sheet tool to adjust the line position.
Now we have the shape of the pleats.
We need to unfold the sheet to fold the pleats.
In the edit sheet tool group, find the second tool to fold the pleats.
This tool is used to separate and unfold the sheets along the lines.
After selecting the fold-over, there will be a prompt.
Click on the line and then draw the baseline line.
That is, you can choose a line as the fold-over baseline line.
When you stop the mouse on a line, you will see the direction arrow.
Now we are going to create a pleats on the right side.
Therefore, we need to make sure that the direction arrow is close to the right waistline,
so that the sheet is also unfolded on the right side, and the pleats are formed at the same time.
Click to select the line, then there is a prompt to select which side to rotate.
To select which side to rotate.
Click to rotate any side.
The pre-selected pleats of the moving mouse are clicked to confirm the position.
Now that we've added certain pleats, we're going to start creating the pleats folding line.
Put the mouse in the edit sheet tool group, and select the add tool.
Click on the line section to open, then select the bottom of the split line window to select the average segment
This function is used to create a uniform segment along the line section
Set the number of lines to 2, you will automatically create a straight line with a uniform segment
Then use the internal line tool to refer to the folding line in the video
Folding a fold line
aí y錯
president
When you have created it, please use the folder in the tool bar upside down to complete folding
Revisit the reference picture till the next use
you can observe that all the folds are folded upwards and follow in the same direction
Click on the fold starting position, 20% gels at the end, choose the folding direction
aamour entered or finished. This will trigger another spread window to confirm about the configuration
The most complicated part of the close up is building a width and lengthing line
каждem
When we open a fold, we all need to re-edit the sewing line
First choose the tool to edit the sewing line
Check the sewing line
You will see that they are sewn in a whole section and a whole section
We need to manually modify these sewing lines
First we need to skip the fold
To create a long sewing line separately
So we need to adjust the sewing line first
Make sure the complicated part isn't too long
When you are done with the first set of sewing line
Skip the fold
Use the free sewing tool to sew up the second length of the line
When we're done, use the free-form tool to continue to sew the pleats
Because the green line is folded inwards, it will stick to the left and right sides, in order to fix the two sides of the line to be sewed together
The corresponding red line is protruding outward, so the two lines on the left and right sides have to be sewed together
When sewing on the left and right sides near the red line, please use the shorter line as the base, and do not sew to the opening position of the pleats
After completion, select this pleat at the 3D window, and then select the 3D arrangement position in the menu in the right-click menu
Use another ball to rotate the moving pleat to the right position
Then repeat the steps until all the pleats are completed
I remind you again to avoid overlapping or covering the sewing line many times, or it may not be stable
When you have created the effect in the picture, we need to add some details to the pleats
In the window of the 2D pleat, select the edit pleat tool
Click and drag the end points of the inner line to adjust them
In order to smooth the pleats too much, you need to move the end point of the folding line to the center of the pleat
Press the Ctrl key to move the end point, you can adjust the line according to the original rhythm of the line
When all the inner lines have been adjusted, the pleats are adjusted
You can see that the pleats have changed when you restarted modeling
Select the whole group of clothing, let's culinary and visualization them
algia is Cocktail
Now look at the 3D window, and you'll see that the pleats are very sharp and hard and a little bit fixed
The здесь 左邊的三個 箱裏 刷在一邊 когда man».
現時查看3D alarman honرت
so we need to adjust the paper to a more natural look
Rename the board again to make it easier to fold and adjust
Re-coil the other extra boards
Then select the Folding Folding Tool
Repeat the previous steps, select a set of internal lines
In default settings, the folding angle is set to 0, 360
When the value is close to 180 degrees, the smaller the fold, the more natural the fold will look
Repeat the steps to adjust all the folding angles from 120 degrees to 240 degrees
Then use the Editing Board Tool
In the blank area on the board, double-click to use the
Selection Function
We will select all the internal lines that form the fold
Click on the starting position to complete the selection
Then adjust them in the attribute editor on the right
When you select the internal line with the fold angle applied
The right side will appear with the option related to the fold
Now we will reduce the intensity to 1
After setting the fold intensity, remove the hardening of the board
Compare the effect in the 3D window
If you are not satisfied with the position of the fold, you can adjust it again
You can use the Editing Board Tool
At the same time, select the three internal lines of a fold and adjust them together
In this way, you can adjust the entire fold
After adjusting, continue to remove the freezing and hardening of the board and then simulate
In the attribute editor, reduce all the particles of the board to 10
In order to make the fold transition more natural
Then we go to the 3D window
Open the clothing frame display
Now the board grid is a triangle
There are some凹凸不平 in the fold position
The function of the fold grid is to make the grid of the board
From the level of the 2D window to the vertical direction
Become the four sides of the law
After folding the board grid
You can see the grid surface of the board in the 3D window
The grid surface of the board will become straight
After opening the simulation
You can see that the shape of the fold is more flat and smooth
Finally, let's modify the fabric physics
Please open the fabric window and click on the fabric of the clothing
In the attribute editor below
We can change the physical properties of the fabric to other default physical properties
Here we choose Silk Dutches Satin
It is a silk fabric that is close to our reference clothing
Change the material type of the fabric to Silk Satin
Can make the fabric look more shiny and more real
In this tutorial
We will use pure fabric for clothing
Click on the small color block and choose the appropriate color in the color palette
Now we have completed this tutorial
If you have any questions, please leave a message in the comments section below
Thank you for your support
See you in the next video